texasattorneygeneral.gov 2015-04-12

# Agency - Site Policies

On this page you can find our office's website privacy and accessibility policies. You can also find ways to contact us if you have concerns about these policies or believe we have violated any of their terms. In addition we provide links from this page to our Open Records policy, our link policy and our Compact with Texans.

## Privacy Policy

Your privacy and security are important to us. We have tried to balance the interest of consumer privacy with the requirements of open government. We will continue to review our website to ensure that we are protecting your privacy as best we can under the law and will update our privacy policy whenever necessary to reflect any relevant changes to our site or our practices.

### Notice

**Collection and use of personally identifiable information:** We do not collect any personally identifiable information, such as names, addresses, phone numbers or email addresses, unless you choose to provide such information, for instance, in the form of an online complaint, as part of our child support interactive service, or to subscribe to our E-Presslist or our E-Opinions list. The information you submit to us in the form of an online complaint will be used by the Attorney General's staff to respond to your complaint and to fulfill our official duties. We do not use "cookies," which are pieces of data stored on the user's hard drive that can be used to track information about browsing habits during multiple visits to the site. If you access our child support interactive services or our website, we do, however, use "server log software" which allows us to collect the following limited navigational information to assist us in managing and improving our website:

  * Your Internet Service Provider. For instance, if you connect to our site using AOL, our system will know that someone using AOL connected to the site. However, your actual identity will not be known. We will not know any personally identifiable information about you, including your name and email address.
  * The date and time that our website was visited.
  * The website from which you accessed our site. For instance, we will know if someone accessed our site through the National Association of Attorneys General website. Your personal identity, however, will not be known.

This information is used internally to help our staff count the number of people visiting our website and the various Web pages within our site. This information helps us to maintain and improve our website for our visitors.

**Disclosure of information:** If you file an on-line complaint form or submit information though the child support interactive service, the information submitted will be disclosed to the Attorney General and his staff to assist us in fulfilling our official duties, as stated above. The information may also be sent to the person or company that is the subject of your complaint or to other governmental agencies involved in the administration or enforcement of the matter. The information will not be disclosed to third parties, unless we receive an open records request _and_ we are required to disclose the information under the Public Information Act. The rules regarding public disclosure of information we receive from online complaints are the same rules that apply to disclosure of information we receive when you file a paper complaint with our office. Protected health information will only be used or disclosed as permitted or required by law. Any information you submit to us online will not be sold, rented or leased to third parties.

With few exceptions, if you complete and file an informational form with the Office of the Attorney General (hereinafter "OAG"), you are entitled on request to be informed about the information that the OAG has collected about you. In most cases, you have the right to receive and review the information. If you request copies of the information, you may be subject to charges authorized under the Public Information Act. Under section 559.004 of the Government Code, you are entitled to have the OAG correct any information the OAG maintains about you that is incorrect. You will not be charged for correcting this information. If you want to review or obtain copies of agency records, please send a written request to the following: [publicrecords@texasattorneygeneral.gov](mailto:publicrecords@texasattorneygeneral.gov).

### Choice

The only personal information we collect from you is information you choose to provide to us in the form of an online complaint or through our interactive child support services.

### Access

If you have a question, concern or change regarding information in a consumer complaint form that was submitted online, please contact us at [consumerprotection@texasattorneygeneral.gov](mailto:consumerprotection@texasattorneygeneral.gov). If you have a question, concern or change regarding information contained in or submitted via our child support interactive service, please contact us at [child.support@texasattorneygeneral.gov](mailto:child.support@texasattorneygeneral.gov.).

### Security

We use a secure socket layer (SSL) and a security certificate to enhance the security of any information you choose to submit to us through our website. In other areas of our website, we provide only the security necessary to maintain our website and information we provide to you as part of our child support interactive services.

### Purpose & Scope

Social media tools are software systems or services provided on the Internet, such as Facebook and Twitter, through which users create online communities or web pages to share information and other content. The Office of the Attorney General (OAG) recognizes that social media tools allow users to quickly and easily share information with one another. In keeping with the OAG's goal of making government open and accessible, the agency may utilize social media tools to post or share information related to official agency business. The purpose of this policy is to ensure that the OAG's use of social media tools for official agency business remains in compliance with any applicable laws and rules. The OAG's Information Technology Security Policy Manual and this policy will govern the agency's use of any social media tool. This policy does not govern OAG employees' personal use of social media tools; employee personal use is still governed by the OAG's Social Media: Personal Use by Employees policy.

### Control & Monitoring

The decision to utilize any social media tool, or create a social media page, shall be made by the First Assistant Attorney General or his/her designee. The OAG's Communications Division shall exclusively control and regularly monitor any OAG social media page or account. No other OAG division or employee may utilize social media tools, or create a social media page, to conduct agency business.

### Information & Privacy

The agency may not post or share information on an OAG social media page if that information is confidential under any law or rule or would be excepted from disclosure under the Public Information Act, Chapter 552 of the Texas Government Code.

Members of the public should not post or share information on an OAG social media page if that information is personal, sensitive, obscene, threatening, harassing, discriminatory, or would otherwise compromise public safety or incite violence or illegal activities.

### Retention, Destruction & Removal of Information

Information posted or shared on an OAG social media page may qualify as public information and/or a state record. Accordingly, such information will be retained or destroyed in accordance with the OAG's Records Retention Schedule and any applicable laws or rules.

Unless otherwise prohibited by law or rule, information posted or shared on an OAG social media page may be removed and/or deleted from the page at any time at the OAG's discretion.

### Intellectual Property

The OAG respects the rights of intellectual property owners and will not intentionally infringe on those rights. The OAG's use of protected intellectual property on an OAG social media page will be in compliance with applicable laws and rules.

The terms of service of the respective social media tool will govern the posting or sharing of intellectual property on an OAG social media page by a member of the public.

If an intellectual property owner believes his/her rights have been infringed by the posting or sharing of intellectual property on an OAG social media page, he/she should contact the OAG at:

> Communications Division  
>  Office of the Attorney General  
>  P.O. Box 12548  
>  Austin, TX 78711-2548
> 
> Phone: (512) 463-2050
> 
> Email: [communications@texasattorneygeneral.gov](mailto:communications@texasattorneygeneral.gov)

### Public Information Requests

The OAG will not accept public information requests submitted through an OAG social media page. In order to request information from the OAG, a written request must be sent by mail, fax or email to the following:

> Public Information Coordinator  
>  Office of the Attorney General  
>  P.O. Box 12548  
>  Austin, TX 78711-2548
> 
> Fax: (512) 494-8017
> 
> Email: [publicrecords@texasattorneygeneral.gov](mailto:publicrecords@texasattorneygeneral.gov)

Further instructions for requesting information from the OAG can be found at: https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/og/how-to-request-public-information

### Linking

The [Texas Department of Information Resources State Website Link Policy](http://www2.dir.state.tx.us/pubs/Pages/weblink-privacy.aspx), which contains guidelines and information on linking to state agency websites, will govern linking to and from an OAG social media page. The OAG does not assume responsibility for the content of linked sites and does not endorse the content, products, services or viewpoints expressed or provided by linked sites.

## Website Link Policy

The Office of the Attorney General's website complies with the [Texas Department of Information Resources State Website Link Policy](http://www2.dir.state.tx.us/pubs/Pages/weblink-privacy.aspx), which contains guidelines and information on linking to State agency websites. Our website also includes links to a variety of other public and private websites. These external sites have been selected based on the relevance of their content to assist visitors in locating additional resources and information on government, law, and other matters within the scope of the agency's duties or of general public concern. Some links to external sites are required by law to be included on our site. The Office of the Attorney General does not assume responsibility for the content of linked sites and does not endorse the content, products, services or viewpoints expressed or provided by linked sites.

## Accessibility Policy

The Office of the Attorney General is committed to making its website accessible to all users. We welcome comments and suggestions to improve the accessibility of our website. Please visit the Electronic and Information Resources Accessibility Policy and Procedures Manual.

If you use assistive technology and the format of any material on our website interferes with your ability to access the information, please contact our Webmaster by email at [**webmaster@texasattorneygeneral.gov**](mailto:webmaster@texasattorneygeneral.gov?subject=Regarding%20Accessibility "Webmaster").

To enable us to respond in the most helpful way, please indicate the nature of the accessibility problem, the preferred format in which to receive the material, the Web address of the requested material, and your contact information. Every attempt will be made to resolve the problem; however, due to technological resource limitations we may be unable to address all issues. You may contact our Accessibility Coordinator by sending an email with "Regarding Accessibility" in the subject line to [**public.information@texasattorneygeneral.gov**](mailto:public.information@texasattorneygeneral.gov?subject=Regarding%20Accessibility "Accessibility%20Coordinator"), or by calling 512-475-4413.

Additional information on accessibility programs in Texas is available from the Governor's Committee on People with Disabilities at [**www.governor.state.tx.us/disabilities/**](http://www.governor.state.tx.us/disabilities/).

## Contacts

_If you have questions about this policy or believe that we have acted in violation of this policy, please send your concerns through ourcontact page or write or call us at:_

> Office of the Attorney General  
>  Public Information & Assistance Division, MC-027  
>  P.O. Box 12548  
>  Austin, TX 78711-2548  
>  Tele: (512) 463-2007 or (800) 252-8011

Visit the contact us section of this site for more information about agency contacts.
